Pradeep Kumar Dhotre

UI & UX Designer mscripts



ABOUT ME

Highly creative designer with 11+ years of strong experience in professional UI/UX Designing, seeking challenging opportunities in your team. With advanced level of expertise in Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, XD & Figma and strong fundamentals in HTML/CSS, can turn complex designs into delightful and compelling user experiences.

EXPERIENCE

mscripts / Associate UI UX Manager JUN 2019 TO PRESENT, BENGALURU, mscripts.com

At present, I lead a team to implement pharmacy-patient engagement products on mobile and web, oversee branding and review UI/UX of the products. Key responsibilities include,

- Own the product design; all the way from kick-off sessions, research exercises, and presenting work to stakeholders throughout the process.
- Collaborate with account managers, sales team, product owners to gather requirements, create wireframes and prototypes, design and demonstrate rich user interfaces, infographics, mailers, illustrations.
- Create and update <u>style guides</u>, patient <u>help/support sites</u> on Drupal (CMS).
- Help developers with required graphic assets and review UI to achieve pixel-perfect designs.
- Participate in campus drives to hire fresh grads for internships.

Senior Specialist - UI / UX JAN 2016 TO JUN 2019

As a senior designer at **mscripts**, I defined designs for enterprise mobile and web apps interfaces and improved user experiences across products.

- Took the lead in transforming our native mobile apps into hybrid apps/progressive web apps (PWA). The Pharmacy section of the Costco Wholesale app in the US is uses mscripts hybrid app (app-in-app).
- Accelerated implementation process by 29%, through unit testing, peer reviews and automated asset creation to be readily available.
- Optimized App UI to comply with ADA (Americans with Disabilities Act) Standards to be Accessible designs.
- I also created infographics, icons, illustrations for the product and UI for in-house utilities and <u>tools</u>, that are used by developers and <u>quality analysts</u>.
- Helped build <u>corporate website</u> and maintain corporate brand identity.
- Former member of the fun/sports committee to organize events at the office.

SKILLS & COMPETENCY

Research: Study analytics data to understand users behaviour. Persona and scenario based user stories. Mind mapping, brainstorming and white boarding. Concept sketching. Strategic approach to HCI.

Designing: Sketch, Figma to create Wireframes and User flows. Photoshop to create UI mock-ups, graphics, illustrations. Illustrator to create vector graphics, Branding Identity, Logo designs, Iconography, Icon fonts.

Prototyping: Rapid prototyping and Interactive flows with Adobe XD & InVision.

Usability Testing: Walkthrough evaluation. Split testing.

Hand-off: Specifications and Assets with style guides and pattern libraries.

Front-end Development: Integrate UI with plain HTML/CSS/basic-JS. Hands-on with frameworks (Bootstrap) and CMS (Drupal, WordPress). Mobile-first and Responsive design. CSS Preprocessors(LESS, SCSS). Browser compatibility. Git and version control. Beginner knowledge on Angular, React and Flutter.

If you use any other tools which suits your workflow, I would be happy to learn them.

Complete Portfolio →

CoStrategix / Lead Designer

NOV 2009 TO DEC 2015, BENGALURU, costrategix.com

My core responsibilities included designing UI for websites and developing UI in plain HTML/CSS (pre-Bootstrap era). Lead a team and mentor them. To collaborate with the account managers on project sprints. I also worked on branding, logo design, graphics, microsites and mobile apps UI.

Noted work at CoStrategix

IACC - naturalForms - ShopViz

CSugeries - Apollo Home - Cincinnati Art Museum PhotoHide Gallery App: **Behance**, **iTunes**

ADDR Technologies / Web Designer

JUN 2008 TO NOV 2009, BENGALURU

I worked as a web designer and as part of my responsibilities included designing UI for simple static websites. Created many icons, illustrations for a social travel network.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (BE) in Polymer Science & Technology Engineering in Sri Jayachamarajendra College of Engineering (SJCE), Mysore, under Visvesvaraya Technological University (VTU) with an aggregate marks of 64 %.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Interactive Resume: http://pdot.in
- Zawn: Enterprise SaaS suite for eco-friendly office
- Logo design for IoT startup: <u>VIWO</u>
 <u>Technologies</u>
- Swakula Matrimony: A free matrimony website, designed logo, website, UI development with Bootstrap.

SOFT SKILLS

Keeping up with design trends by reading tech blogs, participate in community forums. Fluent communication, attention to details. concentration under pressure, time management, creative thinking, collaboration, critical thinking, problem-solving and presentation skills.

I love playing carom, badminton. I'm a music lover, film buff and a foodie.







